<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jekyll-Notes</title>
    <description>Tips and tricks for users of Jekyll, the world&#39;s most popular static site generator.
</description>
    <link>http://jekyll-notes.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://jekyll-notes.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 11:07:31 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 11:07:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll Notes!</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-the-beginning&quot;&gt;In the beginning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first discovered Jekyll in the middle of 2013, when I had decided to teach myself web development. I needed to build a bunch of practice sites on which to practice the CSS arts and using WordPress or any sort of full-stack framework seemed like swatting an ant with an anvil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave Jekyll a try and was immediately hooked. That version came with some really horrid CSS, which most people who tried Jekkyl didn’t bother to change. The current version of Jekyll looks like Medium in comparison to the Geocities-esque in-line styling of the original.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I love writing posts in markdown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I love writing posts in my own text editor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jekyll is small and easy to &lt;em&gt;reason about&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;version control includes my posts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;green squares on GitHub for blog posts  ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;not user friendly for non-techies and there’s no control panel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;you can’t really write posts from you phone, if you’re into that sort of degenerate behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-the-thing-that-comes-after-the-beginning&quot;&gt;In the thing that comes after the beginning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making a Jekyll blog is cool. Customizing that Jekyll blog is cooler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty easy to get up and running with Jekyll, but judging by the number of Jekyll blogs I’ve seen that have the default page structure, it looks like most people take a look at Liquid (the templating language that powers Jekyll) and they just say, “Nah.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is about digging into Jekyll, getting our hands dirty, and finding ways to bend Jekyll to our will.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 07:55:58 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jekyll-notes.com/jekyll/update/2015/01/06/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jekyll-notes.com/jekyll/update/2015/01/06/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
